Guide to the Klaus Reikowski papers, 1954-1976 and undated RL.01077
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Klaus Reikowski papers
1954-1976 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
Reikowski, Klaus
RL.01077
1554
4.0 Linear Feet
Advertising executive, art director and graphic designer with the Cunningham & Walsh advertising agency in New York City. Collection includes prints, sketches, gels, photos, catalogues, correspondence, a set of logo design sketches for Cross Westchester Corporate Park, a drawing of an automobile by George or Robert Giusti and a sketch on a linen napkin from the restaurant Nicola Paone. Companies represented in include Amerika-Haus, Cunningham & Walsh, Boise Cascade Paper Company, St. Regis Paper Company, Herman Miller, Inc., Jaguar automobile, Sunshine Biscuits, Inc. (Kellogg), Western Electric Company (AT & T Technologies, Inc.), and Yellow Pages. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising and Marketing History.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Klaus Reikowski papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase in 2006 and 2007.
Biographical Note
Reikowski was an art director and graphic designer who worked for Cunningham & Walsh advertising agency in New York City. He immigrated to the U.S. in 1958 from Germany, where he had worked with the U.S. Information Service, designing promotional materials for Amerika Haus. As an art director at Cunningham & Walsh, he worked with clients including Sunshine Biscuits, Herman Miller, and General Foods. He attended art school at the Meisterschule fuer Graphik in Berlin and was drafted into the German army as a private, first class during WWII.
Scope and Contents note
Collection includes prints, sketches, gels, photos, catalogues, correspondence, a set of logo design sketches for Cross Westchester Corporate Park, a drawing of an automobile by George or Robert Giusti and a sketch on a linen napkin from the restaurant Nicola Paone. Companies represented in include Amerika-Haus, Cunningham & Walsh, Boise Cascade Paper Company, St. Regis Paper Company, Herman Miller, Inc., Jaguar automobile, Sunshine Biscuits, Inc. (Kellogg), Western Electric Company (AT & T Technologies, Inc.), and Yellow Pages. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising and Marketing History.
Brand name products -- Marketing; Advertising -- Brand name products; Advertising executives -- United States; Amerika Haus; Container Corporation of America; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; Herman Miller; General Foods Corporation; Reikowski, Klaus; Sunshine Biscuits
- Klaus Reikowski papers, 1954-1976 and undated; 1
  - Amerika Haus, 1954-1955 (Box 1)
  - Boise Cascade Paper Group Promotional Magazine, undated (Box 3)
    Scope and Contents
    Magazine on major boxing matches of twentieth century
  - Car Drawing by Giusti, undated (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1957-1958 (Box 1)
  - Cross Westchester Corporate Park Logo Sketches, undated (Box 1)
  - Cunningham and Walsh Mailing Lists and Organizational Charts, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Gels, undated (Box 1)
  - General Foods Post Cereals, undated (Box 2)
  - General Foods Prints and Sketches, undated (Box 1)
  - Herman Miller Photos and Sketches, undated (Box 2)
  - Herman Miller Cardstock, undated; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Herman Miller Cardstock, undated (Box 2)
  - Herman Miller Catalogues, 1959 (Box 1)
  - Herman Miller Catalogues, 1960 (Box 2)
  - Herman Miller Photos, undated (Box 1)
  - Herman Miller Prints, 1959-1960; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Herman Miller Prints, 1959 (Box 2)
  - Herman Miller Sketches, undated (Box 1)
  - Jaguar Prints and Sketches, 1963 (Box 2)
  - Jaguar Prints Sketches and Gels, 1962 and undated (Box 1)
  - Linen Napkin Sketch Nicola Paone, undated (Box 2)
  - Sketches, undated (Box 2)
    Western Electeric, Revlon [?]; General Foods Post Honeycomb
  - St. Regis Paper Company Promotional Calendar, 1976 (Box 3)
  - Sunshine Brand Placement Sketches, undated (Box 3)
  - Sunshine Hi Ho Sketches, undated (Box 3)
  - Sunshine Hi Ho Cardstock, undated (Box 4)
  - Sunshine Hi Ho Hydrox and Krispy Cracker Prints and Proofs, 1962 and undated (Box 4)
  - Sunshine Hydrox Gels, undated (Box 1)
  - Sunshine Hydrox Prints, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Sunshine Hydrox Sketches, undated (Box 3)
  - Sunshine Krispy Cracker Gels, undated (Box 4)
  - Sunshine Krispy Crackers Cardstock, undated (Box 4)
  - Sunshine Krispy Crackers Drafts, undated (Box 1)
  - Sunshine Krispy Crackers Sketches, undated; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Western Electric Prints, 1961-1962 (Box 1)
  - Western Electric Prints and Sketches, 1961 (Box 2)
  - Yellow Pages Prints, 1963 (Box 2)